Finding Aid for Zonta Club of Owosso records, 1929-2006
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Zonta Club of Owosso records 1929-2006
Zonta Club of Owosso.
0719 Bk 2
The Zonta Club of Owosso records (1929-2006) consist of founding documents, bylaws, correspondence, notes, conference proceedings, board meeting minutes and agendas, newsletters, newsletters from its international district, scrapbooks, audio-visual materials, and other records documenting the administrative duties of the club. The Zonta Club of Owosso is one of many local units of Zonta International, a global organization of executives and professionals working together to advance the status of women worldwide through service and advocacy.
9 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was received from the organization (donor no. 9810 ) and came through Ann Bentley, former president, in November 2006.
The record group is open to research.
Zonta International is a worldwide service organization of executives in business and the professions working together to advance the status of women. Started in 1919 by the first-generation of women voters and college graduates, Zonta International required its members to be employed at least 50% of the time at executive or decision-making levels, in a variety of business classifications. The Zonta Club of Owosso, Michigan was chartered in 1929. The Owosso charter has maintained a solid membership since its beginning. The Zonta Club of Owosso is part of District 15, which stretches through Michigan and Ontario, Canada. Zonta International and District 15 both have an annual meeting, of which Owosso is usually represented and has had members sit as officers in both agencies.
The objectives of the Zonta Club of Owosso are to stimulate the desire of each member to be of service; to promote good fellowship as an opportunity for service; and to quicken the interest of each member in the welfare of this community and to corporate with others in its civic, social, commercial, and industrial development. The Zonta Club of Owosso and its committees meet regularly, at least once a month. Members serve on a variety of local, regional, and international committees, including archives, financial, literacy, membership, public relations, scholarships, service, United Nations, and Women's Health. Members are active in the community and help social and community causes, including work with fundraising and donations, local schools and children, and coordinating events and speakers. The Zonta Club of Owosso has a web site available for view at: http://www.zontadistrict15.org/owosso/.
The Zonta Club of Owosso records (1929-2006) consist of founding documents, bylaws, correspondence, notes, conference proceedings, board meeting minutes and agendas, newsletters, newsletters from its designated Zonta district in Michigan, scrapbooks, audio-visual materials, and other records documenting the administrative duties of the club. The record group is divided into three series, Chronological Files (5 linear feet), Visual Materials (1 linear foot), and Scrapbooks (3 linear feet).
Subjects:
Zonta Club of Owosso.; Owosso (Mich.); Women--Michigan--Owosso--Societies and clubs.; Zonta International.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Zonta Club of Owosso.; Owosso (Mich.); Women--Michigan--Owosso--Societies and clubs.; Zonta International.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Videotapes.
- Chronological Files 1929-2006
  The Chronological Files consist of folders arranged by year from 1929 to 2006. Materials found in these folders may contain founding documents, by-laws, correspondence, project files, board meeting agendas and minutes, and conference files for the Owosso area, Zonta District, and the Zonta International Conference files.
  - 1929-1959, 31 folders (Box 1)
    (certificate of membership, 1929, located in oversize box 9)
  - 1960-1977, 18 folders (Box 2)
  - 1978-1985, 8 folders (Box 3)
  - 1986-1996, 11 folders (Box 4)
  - 1997-2006, 10 folders (Box 5)
  - 1990s (Box 5)
- Visual Materials 1939-2003
  The Visual Material series consists of photographs, video, and slides. The photographs range from 1939 to 2003 and are mostly of members at local, regional, and international meetings and conferences. The 70th Anniversary of the Zonta Club of Owosso in 1999 is captured on VHS and 8mm. The slides range from 1968 to 1971 and focus on regional and international conferences.
  - Photographs
    - 1939-1949 (Box 6)
    - 1950-1969 (Box 6)
    - 1968-1971 (scrapbook) (Box 6)
    - 1970-1979 (Box 6)
    - 1980-1989 (Box 6)
    - 1990-1999 (Box 6)
    - June 1997-May 1998 (scrapbook) (Box 6)
    - 2000-2003 (Box 6)
  - Videotape
    - 70th Anniversary 1999, VHS and 8mm (Box 6)
  - Slides
    - Cleveland Conference 1968 (Box 6)
    - Zonta Inter City 1971 (Box 6)
    - Zonta Christmas 1970 (Box 6)
    - Zonta International Convention, Chicago 1970 (Box 6)
    - Zonta International Convention, Minneapolis 1968 (Box 6)
    - Zonta District V, Traverse City 1968 (Box 6)
    - Zonta 40th Anniversary 1969 (Box 6)
- Scrapbooks 1939-2003
  The Scrapbook series includes regular and oversize materials, ranging from 1939 to 2003. Many scrapbooks are of international conferences, as well as scrapbooks of specific years of the local club.
  - "Items about new members" (Box 7)
  - June 1941-June 1943 (Box 7)
  - June 1943-June 1944 (Box 7)
  - June 1947-June 1948 (Box 7)
  - June 1948-June 1949 (Box 7)
  - June 1949-June 1950 (Box 7)
  - June 1953-June 1954 (Box 7)
  - 1956-1959 (Box 7)
  - 1964-1969 (Box 7)
  - 1968-1969 (Box 7)
  - 1970-1976 (Box 7)
  - Newspaper clippings circa 1970-2000, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - 1963-1989 (Box 8)
  - Ann Bentley scrapbook 2001-2003 (Box 8)
  - Detroit International Conference 1994 (Box 8)
  - Laminated scrapbook 1934-1937 (Box 9)
  - Honolulu Club -- 1937 Program in Niagara Falls, NY (Box 9)
  - July 1937-March 1940 (Box 9)